Mob: +6281310237633

Email: bhaskynateshan@gmail.com

M N Bhaskaran

Profile

A Innovative and accomplished Top Management Professional and a natural leader with over 32 years of quality experience and successful track-record in leading large organizations of global repute and delivering outstanding business results across industries, continents and cultures.

Experience

Present

Freelance consultant:

Details

Job profile (presently stationed at Indonesia):

- Provide technical inputs for optimizing manufacturing operations of Caustic Chlorine, EDC, VCM and PVC facilities.
- Introduced cost savings to the tune of around 2 million USD with minimum investment.
- Increased production across the facilities thru innovative practices. Caustic soda from 890 MTPD to 930 MTPD, VCM from around 385 MTPD to 395 MTPD and PVC from PVC from around 335 MTPD to around 342 MTPD.
- Identified saving opportunities to the tune of another 5 million USD, with investment.
- Negotiated with some of the vendors for providing low interest loans to the tune of 50% plus of the investment.

August 2009 – July 2015

Nagarjuna Fertilizers and Chemicals Ltd

President – Sustainable Upstream business & Executive Vice President – Downstream Business

Job profile:

- Joined as VP Operations to be groomed to take up the role of COO for the Rs. 5500 Crore fertilizer operations, and promoted within a year for the exemplary performance and leadership.
- Heading the entire Downstream Business for the organization encompassing Sales & Marketing, Supply Chain, R&D along with heading other national and international subsidiaries.
- Increased top line from Rs. 2000 crores in 2009-10 to Rs. 5000 crores in 2011-12.
- Increased the bottom-line of traded products from 16 crores (2008-09) to 105 crores (2011 – 12).

- Designed and executed many high impact business strategies, and promoted the concept of being a one stop supplier and entered into the P&K segment in a significant way from 2010-11. (In 2011-12 imports of P&K have been around 9 lakh MT).
- Highly regarded and recognized in the Agri Inputs industry as a Turnaround specialist and aggressive strategist. Have had many awards, citations and representations in this regard.
- Forged long term strategic tie-ups with leading global suppliers of P&K., and travelled extensively across the globe and created a strong brand image for Nagarjuna in the International arena.
- Embarked on a strong pan-India presence in the entire product range, visible through increased imported urea quantities by successfully bidding and acquiring the right to handle urea in the ports of Khandla in west coast, Krishnapatnam and Gangavaram in the east coast.
- Strategized a road-map to explore the **International markets** through rapid **Organic and Inorganic growth**. (JV's, M&A's and other entry strategies).
 - Eminent speaker and invitee in national and international forums and conferences. Represented Indian Fertilizer industry at "China International Nitrogen Fertilizer and Methanol Conference" held in June 2012 and numerous other FAI conferences and meets. http://www.cnfia.com.cn/cn/hye/Agenda.html
- Invited to speak in China on Indian Fertilizer market again in the year 2014.
- Speaker at FAI, annual conference in the years 2010 and 2011 apart from chairing many other state level conferences.
- Liaisioning with state and central government officials in the departments of Fertilizers and Agriculture.

1981–1985 (First 4 year batch), Anna University, Madras

Education:

B.Tech Chemical Engineering.

Graduated in first class with distinction.

Personal

Date of Birth: 22nd July 1963 (53 Years)

Details: Marital Status: Married

Family Details: Wife - Housewife

Daughter (20 Years) Son (14 Years)